Surin Cham

Front End Web Developer

Ability to adapt to ever changing environment and strong sense of problem solving. A highly driven and motivated Systems Analyst with years of experience in the healthcare industry. Recognized as quick learner, persistent, detail oriented, outgoing, and a committed team player who strive to achieve deadlines and goals.



present

Experience

Systems Analyst/System Support 2016-07 -

Schryver Medical Sales & Marketing, LLC

- Conduct testing/troubleshooting of new software/software versions for system upgrades.
- Configure and updated system to ensure proper functionality of software.
- Troubleshoot front end user's system operational issues.
- Complete AD HOC report request in a timely matter; including testing and data validation.
- Provide application and insurance website support to front end user via email, phone, or in person.
- Write and updated policy and procedures for users training manual.
- Train front end users on new system functionality and process.

Account Receivable Specialist 2014-10 -2016-06

Schryver Medical Sales & Marketing, LLC

- Reviewed Medicare/Insurance denials in a timely matter to ensure proper timely payments.
- Reviewed patient's accounts with a remaining balance left from insurance.
- Analyzed EOB's received from the insurance companies and take appropriate action; including appealing all claims that are denied or underpaid.
- Obtained proper documentation required from Insurance companies to collect payments.
- Analyzed medical claims for proper action; i.e. to be adjusted off or to further pursue action on monetary collection.
- Advised managers and leaderships of any trends regarding insurance denials, in order to identify problems with particular payers.

2012-12 -

2014-09

Payment Posting

Schryver Medical Sales & Marketing, LLC

- Posted payments from insurance companies.
- Adjusted non-covered charges that are denied by insurance companies.
- Posted denials from insurance companies.
- Posted withholds/credits/take backs.
- Downloaded EOB's from EDI Clearinghouse online.

2011-05 -2012-11

Account Receivable Specialist

Schryver Medical Sales & Marketing, LLC

- Reviewed Medicare/Insurance denials in a timely matter to ensure proper timely payments.
- Reviewed patient's accounts with a remaining balance left from insurance.
- Analyzed EOB's received from the insurance companies and take appropriate action; including appealing all claims that are denied or underpaid.



Personal Info

Address

17066 E Ohio Dr Apt 301 Aurora, CO. 80017

Phone

720-454-8467

E-mail

nirus.surin@gmail.com

GitHub

https://github.com/surincham

LinkedIn

http://linkedin.com/in/surin-cham-551046135



Education

2019-01 - present

University of Denver

Full Stack Web Developer

2016-05 - 2018-12

Community College of

Aurora

Associate of Applied Science Degree of Computer Information **Systems**



Certificates

2017-12

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt

2017-09

Lean Six Sigma White Belt



Skills

HTML

Cascading Style Sheet (CSS)

JavaScript

jQuery

Bootstrap

C++

- Obtained proper documentation required from Insurance companies to collect payments.
- Analyzed medical claims for proper action; i.e. to be adjusted off or to further pursue action on monetary collection.
- Advised managers and leaderships of any trends regarding insurance denials, in order to identify problems with particular payers.

2008-09 - Lab Biller

2011-04

Schryver Medical Sales & Marketing, LLC

- Separated patient's requisitions to be either billed to a facility or to the insurance.
- Entered patient's demographic information from the requisitions.
- Called nursing facilities to get correct patient's demographic information.
- Verified patient's insurance information to determine how charges need to be billed.
- Entered correct charges to be billed to the insurance companies.

SQL

Microsoft Visual Studio

Xcode

SQL Server Management Studio

Microsoft SQL Server

Microsoft Office

Telcor

RapidRad

Copia

CareVoyant

Crystals

Windows OS

Mac OS